# **Carl Storms**

# Technology Evangelist | BIM Crusader | AECO Professional

With 25+ years of AECO experience, Carl excels in BIM and VDC, blending innovation with practicality. A curious learner of coding, automation, and AI-driven solutions, he explores cutting-edge technologies and shares insights through blogging, speaking. Always eager to discuss the latest industry workflows and trends.

carl	.storm	s@gm	nail.com	

1 403 554 0564

Ш

 $\bowtie$ 

Calgary, AB, Canada

•

bio.link/thebimsider



github.com/TheBIMsider



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Technical Success Manager**

#### Newforma

01/2020 - Present

- Driving product adoption and customer success through advocacy and education.
- Equipped sales teams with industry knowledge, product demos, and strategic insights, to improve conversion rates and streamline the sales process.
- Conducted in-depth analysis of current and emerging industry platforms, creating training materials and content to inform sales strategies and product positioning. Oversee special projects within the organization for emerging technologies.

#### **Solutions Consultant**

# **IMAGINIT Technologies**

08/2012 - 01/2020

- Assess client's current business processes to recommend and implement solutions and application support for client BIM workflows
- Deliver application training to our clients, and industry-related technical presentations at seminars, workshops, conferences, user groups, both onsite and remotely. Customize training solutions where applicable
- Act as a brand ambassador seizing opportunities to increase IMAGINIT's visibility in the AEC marketplace

## BIM Coordinator, IFP - Calgary International Airport

## EllisDon Construction Services

05/2011 - 08/2012

- Led BIM/VDC coordination on projects, facilitating consultants, trades, and subcontractors through project phases.
- Managed 3D modeling processes for estimating, scheduling, logistics, and coordination, ensuring project-specific implementation.
- Provided project deployment support, including software setup, training, and 4D scheduling collaboration.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Architectural Technician Diploma**

Algonquin College

1995 – 1998

#### **SKILLS**

ACC/BIM360 | AI Prompts | APIs | AutoCAD
BIM | CSS | Dynamo | HTML | JavaScript | LLMs
MS Office | Navisworks | Power BI | Revit | VDC
Newforma Konekt | VS Code

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Mentorship | Storytelling | Thought Leadership

# SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS

165+ Presentations at Conferences, Trade Shows, User Groups, Webinars and Other Industry Events

AU, BCS, BILT, bSNC, DBWa, DCW, HxGN, RTC & more 2013 - Present

 For over 10 years, I've had the privilege of speaking worldwide about BIM, VDC, AECO, and AI - from major conferences to local user groups, live or virtual. Along the way, I've been honored as a top speaker eight times. <u>Full list here.</u>

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Speaker Mentor, SME

**Autodesk University** 

2018, 2023 – Present

## Caregiver, Foster & Fundraiser

Cats Home Foundation & CATE

08/2022 - Present

#### **Industry Expert**

CCA, AECO Task Force on BIM

03/2015 - 08/2018

#### **INTERESTS**

3D Printing | AI | Animals | Blogging | Low-Code Coding | Music | No-Code | Podcasting | Sports Making (Building & Tinkering) | Technology